

Summary

More than 6 years of experience mainly with backend related technologies.

Also interested in DevOps and data science solutions as well.

Eager to continuously learn while working on meaningful projects within a team.

Highly values a culture built on empathy, feedback and knowledge sharing.

Contact



+41-78-226-9371

🕑 Zürich, Switzerland

zoltan.umlauf@gmail.com

in /in/zoltan-umlauf

Languages

English: full professional proficiency

German: elementary proficiency Hungarian: native proficiency

Zoltán Umlauf

Senior Software Engineer

Work Experience



Senior Software Engineer

@ UBS (employed by EPAM)

Zürich, 02/2023 - Present C

- Contributed to a suite of services responsible for sourcing Swiss client data for a complex Anti-Money Laundering (AML) model.
- Built GitLab CI/CD pipelines from scratch, enhancing deployment efficiency and establishing a robust workflow for our team.
- Advocated for the importance of fast feedback loops and engineers owning their code in production, even in a regulated industry.
- Fostered good relationships with developers from the upstream team, ensuring satisfactory coordination between our teams.

📚 Java 17, Spring Boot, Maven, Python, Azure Cloud, Databricks, Gitlab CI/CD, Kubernetes, Helm, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL

Senior Software Engineer

@ Turbine Al

Budapest, 09/2021 - 01/2023 0

- · Designed and developed new features in Turbine's human cell simulation platform, making the jobs of biologists more efficient.
- · Constructed machine learning problems to train deep learning models. Evaluated these models on various success criteria.
- Explored various technologies, such as version-controlled databases, while gaining insights into human cell modeling and the drug discovery process.
- Significantly improved the quality of existing production code.
- · Performed a wide range of data engineering tasks.

📚 Python, Poetry, Pandas, Azure Cloud, AzureML, Databricks, Airflow, GitHub Actions, Terraform, Dolt, MongoDB

Senior Software Developer

@ Grape Solutions

Budapest, 03/2019 - 08/2021 0

- · Developed Mobiliti, the largest provider of electric vehicle charging and other e-mobility services in Hungary.
- Discussed software architecture decisions with the team.
- · Improved the development workflow, which reduced the complexity of our releases and increased productivity.
- · Documented important domain knowledge, promoted knowledge sharing and gathering practices.
- Planned and executed the integration with 4 Charge Point Operators.
- Learned the basics of DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes.

Interests

- Table tennis
- Reading
- Board games
- Hiking
- Logic puzzles
- · Software craftsmanship

🤝 Java 11, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2, Reactive Streams, Liquibase, JUnit5, Mockito, Wiremock, Gradle, Docker, Google Cloud Platform (PubSub, Firestore), MySQL, MongoDB, Python

Software Developer

@ AITIA International

Budapest, 06/2017 - 02/2019 Q

- Participated in a European research and innovation project with 108 partners from over 19 countries. Contributed to the design and development of a framework for the project over the span of 3 years. Familiarized new partners with the framework and reviewed code written by them.
- Analysed large amounts of CAN bus data from a German forklift manufacturing company. Communicated with the company representatives to gain domain knowledge. Created classical machine learning models to help reduce forklift maintenance costs.



📚 Java 8, JAX-RS, Spring Boot 2, Hibernate, Maven, RabbitMQ, R

Education

MSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of Technology and Economics 02/2016 - 01/2018

 Thesis: Data processing methods and solutions in IoT based Cyber-Physical Systems

BSc in Electrical Engineering

@ Budapest University of **Technology and Economics**

09/2012 - 01/2016

Thesis: Messaging system aided by speech recognition on Android